## Changkun Ou

**J** +49 157 7214 1480 / +86 186 1322 5636

**✓** contact@changkun.de

Online version: https://changkun.de/s/resume

Last updated: May 17, 2022

# Resume

@changkun 😯 changkun.de 🏶

## Introduction

I am a Ph.D. candidate in human-computer interaction at the Institute of Informatics, LMU Munich (Germany). My research is about human-in-the-loop 3D graphics systems in which I use machine learning to explore and exploit human preferences and improving their decision making. Thus, my research is in interdisciplying between machine learning, 3D graphics, and user modeling.

## **EDUCATION**

## Ph.D. Student Media Informatics (Dr. rer. nat.)

Feb. 2019 - (exp.) Feb. 2023

LMU Munich

• Advisors: Prof. Dr. Andreas Butz (Erstberichterstatter), Prof. Dr. Eyke Hüllermeier (Zweitberichterstatter)

ici)

Oct. 2016 - Jan. 2019

LMU Munich; overall grade: 1.63 (max. 1.0) between "Very Good" and "Good"

Munich, Germany

Munich, Germany

• Thesis: "Understanding and Predicting Web Browsing Behavior"

Master Student Human-Computer Interaction (M.Sc.)

o Advisors: Dr. Daniel Buschek, Dr. Malin Eiband, Prof. Dr. Heinrich Hußmann

**Bachelor Student Computer Science and Engineering (B.Eng.)** 

Sep. 2012 - Jul. 2016

Southwest University for Nationalities; overall grade: 3.74 (max. 4.0), "Top 1" of 154 students

• Thesis: "Designing Alternative Contact-free Control Modalities for Smart Watches"

• Advisor: Prof. Dr. Yaxi Chen

Chengdu, China

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Associate Aprl. 2018 - Present

LMU Munich Munich, Germany

- As researcher: research on human-in-the-loop machine learning 3D graphics systems
- · As teacher: teach 12 classes (as lecturer/instructor/assistant/tutor), and supervising 20+ student theses and seminars
- As developer: develop a 3D mesh processing backend system in collaboration with industry partner WAY digital solutions; develop, migrate, and maintain a 17 year-old university CMS system, and a 13 year-old collaborative system

#### **Backend Software Engineer (Remote)**

Apr. 2018 - Jan. 2019

LabEx Technology Ltd

Munich, Germany

- **As team leader**: leading developments of an oversea product; established microservice based backend architecture; the product autoscales cloud instances (on AWS/AlibabaCloud) ranging from 20 to 200; the product user group grows from 5k+ to 30k+ during my incumbency.
- As developer: 1) developed a scalable remote desktop proxy (support WebSocket to VNC/RDP/SSH protocols) using Go; 2) developed an
  automated multi-cloud resource management microservice that abstracts cross cloud providers (supports AWS/AlibabaCloud over 15 cloud
  products, e.g., IAM/EC2/VPC/etc), scales and used by 10k+ users; 3) developed a kubernetes-like container and instance hybrid management
  service.
- Involved techniques: Frontend: Vue, jQuery, Webpack, Electron; Backend: Go, Cgo, Gin, Beego, gRPC, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Hypervisor, Nginx, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, AlibabaCloud, etc

## **Fullstack Engineer (Freelance)**

Nov. 2017 - Mar. 2018

Rocketlingo UG

Munich, Germany

- **As developer**: developed a voice bot to support novice language learner to improve their language skills by real-time voice recognition and synthesis (supports web and Amazon Alexa), optimize for audio streaming and multilingual falt tolerances using machine learning
- Involved techniques: TypeScript; WebSocket; Angular; Google Cloud STT and TTS; Sklearn; Voice Recognition; etc

## **OPEN SOURCE ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS**

A public statistics indicates that I have earned 18.2k+ stars, 14.2k+ total code commits, 30 contributed open source projects. A public contribution ranking indicates I am a **top 200 developer in Germany** or a **top 100 developer in China**. See github.com/changkun for more authored softwares (including frameworks/tools). Here lists a few selected activities and organizations:

- Go (organization member): an open sourced programming language developed by a team at Google, and have approx. 2 million developer users in the globe. I am one of the official Go organization member (163 people in total), current maintainer of x/mobile repository, active contributor to language runtime and standard library.
- fyne (organization member): an open sourced cross platform GUI framework written in Go, and I am one of the organization member (12 people in total), mainly contributing to graphics and mobile drivers, performance improvements.
- The golang.design Initiative (founder): I created the organization. The organization currently hosts 25 software projects and 6 core members. The organization website have 465k+ page views and 66k+ historical viewers in total since Sep 2020.
- The TalkGo community (organization member): I am a core member of the organization. The community organizes weekly public tech talks, currently have 6.35k+ subscribers, organized 132 public talks. I contributed 7 talks, and they are one of the most viewed talks.
- Juejin Translation Community (organization member): Major contributor, translated 50+ articles from English to Chinese.
- Occasional contributions: Tensorflow (164+ stars), etcd (39.6k+ stars), etc.

#### EXPERTISE AND SKILLS

Expertise is context- and comparison-dependent. Here states the years of experience in terms of use, also indicates a subjective estimation of the level of expertise (either *intermediate*, *experienced*, or *expert*):

- Domain: Computer graphics (3D rendering and geometry processing, 3 years of Bachelors level teaching at university, 2 years of Masters level teaching, Blender/OpenGL/Metal/three.js, experienced); Machine learning (1 year of Masters level teaching at university, Andrew Ng's Deep Learning Specialization Certificate (ID: QGH8ZVJ6J2L2), Sklearn/Tensorflow/PyTorch/etc, experienced); Data analysis (3 years of PhD research, numpy/seaborn/pandas/etc., experienced); Web development (2 years of industrial backend engineering, Go/React/etc., experienced).
- Language: Go (5 years+, expert); Python (4+ years, experienced); JavaScript/TypeScript (5+ years, experienced); C/C++ (2+ years, intermediate); ETeX (10+ years, intermediate). I speak native Mandarin; fluent professional English; elementary German.

## SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS

ACM SIGCHI Special Recognitions (CHI '20) Outstanding Reviews	Nov. 2019  Munich, Germany
Siemens AILab Hackathon 2nd Winner	Nov. 2017  Munich, Germany
China National Scholarship University of Electronic Science and Technology of China	<b>Sep. 2016</b> Chengdu, China
Excellent Bachelor Thesis Award Southwest University for Nationalities	<b>Jun. 2016</b> Chengdu, China
Best University Graduates Award Sichuan Province	<b>Jan. 2016</b> Chengdu, China
China National Scholarship Southwest University for Nationalities	<b>Sep. 2014</b> Chengdu, China
Meritorious Winner in American Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM' 14)  Southwest University for Nationalities	<b>Apr. 2014</b> Chengdu, China